Finding Aid for Maude Elaine Caldwell Perry papers, 1891-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Maude Elaine Caldwell Perry papers 1891-1948
Perry, Maude Elaine Caldwell, 1873-1963.
852158 Aa 2
Author from Adrian, Michigan; correspondence, manuscripts of books, plays, short stories and poetry.
3.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of C. Kenneth Wesley (donor no. 3543 ) and came to the library in 1972.
The collection is open to research.
Maude Elaine Caldwell, was born at Byron, Michigan, in 1873, the daughter of Dr. William Caldwell and Arrilla Cook Caldwell of Fremont, Ohio. She was educated at the University of Michigan, attending (not continuously) in the period of 1889 to 1896. She did not graduate, but met her future husband Stuart H. Perry there. They married in 1895. From 1896 to 1902 they lived at Pontiac, where Perry practiced law for several years in partnership with his father Aaron Perry. Stuart Perry later became editor of the Pontiac Daily Press. In 1902 he bought the St. Johns News, at St. Johns, where they lived until 1907 when he purchased the Adrian Telegram from D.W. Grandon. At this time, they moved to Adrian.
Maude Perry was the author of numerous works of fiction and poetry. Her novel Tide House was published in America in 1929 and in England in 1930. Her writings appeared in such publications as the Atlantic Monthly, the Century Magazine, and other periodicals.
Maude Perry was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, a university honor society, the Authors' League of America, and the Daughters of the American Revolution. She died in 1963.
The collection is arranged into three series: Correspondence; Writings and related materials; and Other Materials (which includes a diary of a trip to Italy in 1895 and a notebook from a bicycle tour made in Europe in 1899). Much of the correspondence is with her husband Stuart H. Perry and with her children and grandchildren.
Subjects:
Adrian (Mich.); Authors, American--Michigan.; Authors, American--Michigan--Adrian.; Bicycle touring--Europe.; Cycling.; Europe--Description and travel.; Perry, Maude Elaine Caldwell, 1873-1963.; Poetry.; Travelers--Europe.; Voyages and travels.; Women authors, American--Michigan--Adrian.; Women travelers--Europe.
Contributors:
Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.; Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918.; Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Correspondence
  - Various
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1891-1900 (Box 1)
      (include letter from John Dewey, June 6, 1894, Walter H. Page, 1898, and Fred Newton Scott)
    - 1901-1915 (Box 1)
    - 1916-1920 (Box 1)
    - 1921-1925 (Box 1)
      (include letter from Frank Manny, 1925)
    - 1926-1928 (Box 1)
    - 1929 (Box 1)
    - 1930 (Box 1)
      (include letter from Frank Manny)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 1)
    - 1933 (Box 1)
    - 1934 (Box 1)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1941-1944 (Box 1)
    - 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - With Stuart H. Perry
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1898-1900 (Box 1)
    - 1912 (Box 1)
    - 1913-1921 (Box 1)
    - 1922-1925 (Box 1)
    - 1926 (Box 1)
    - 1927-1929 (Box 1)
    - 1930-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1934 (Box 1)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1947 (Box 1)
  - With the Perry children and grandchildren
    - Undated, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - 1909-1915 (Box 1)
    - 1916-1918 (Box 2)
    - January 1919 (Box 2)
    - February 1919 (Box 2)
    - March 1919 (Box 2)
    - April 1919 (Box 2)
    - May-December 1919 (Box 2)
    - 1920-1930 (Box 2)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 2)
    - 1936-1938 (Box 2)
    - 1939 (Box 2)
    - 1940 (Box 2)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 2)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946 (Box 2)
    - 1947 (Box 2)
    - 1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949 (Box 2)
    - 1950 (Box 2)
    - 1951 (Box 2)
    - 1952 (Box 2)
    - 1953 (Box 2)
    - 1954 (Box 2)
    - 1955, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - 1956, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Letters from Maude Perry to her mother concerning a trip to Europe 1899, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Letters to Elizabeth Perry from G. C. Currie (Canadian soldier in World War I)
    - 1913-1915 (Box 2)
    - 1916 (Box 2)
    - 1917 (Box 2)
    - 1918 (Box 2)
    - 1919 (Box 2)
- Writings and related
  - Author's League of America 1927-1937 (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of Novel Tide House, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Reviews of novel ide House, 1929-1930, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of novel The Yellow Rose Bush, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of play The Vow, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of novel Sea's Edge, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Poems 1893-1925 (Box 3)
  - Short stories 1894-1936, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Short stories 1894-1936, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Other materials
  - Notebook concerning bicycle tour of Europe 1899 (Box 4)
  - Diary of trip through Italy, 1895 (Box 4)
  - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 4)